Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/renjie-chencmt-433a613 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Risk Management Analytics Valuation

Renjie Chen, CMT

Data Scientist at Black Knight, Inc Orange County, California Area

Summary

Mortgage Bankers Association certified Mortgage Technologist specialized in Automated Valuation Models (AVMs or automated appraisals) architecture and development for residential real estate internationally. Particularly interested in AVM business stratergy and brand development as well as branding.

Specialties: applied mathematics, business intelligent system, software development, and risk management

Experience

Black Knight, Inc Data Scientist October 2017 - Present (2 years 6 months) Irvine,CA

Applying intelligence-gathering technologies to develop sophisticated models and algorithms to discover data knowledge and identity business opportunities.

Implementing innovative and effective business applications for real estate collateral risk management

Black Knight Financial Services Data & Analytics (Now part of Black Knight, Inc)
Data Scientist
January 2014 - October 2017 (3 years 10 months)
Irvine, CA

Maintained and improved the automated real estate property valuation system for the 30+ trillion U.S. housing market

Lender Processing Services, Inc. (Now part of Black Knight, Inc) Senior Vice President, AVM Analytics February 2010 - January 2014 (4 years)

Designed and implemented the automated real estate property valuation system for 100+ million U.S. homes

Page 1 of 2

First American Core Logic (Now part of CoreLogic) Sr. Director, Collateral Solutions August 2005 - February 2010 (4 years 7 months)

Architected, designed, and implemented Automated Valuation Models (AVMs) to value residential properties.

Developed first-class AVMs for United States, United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand mortgage lending industries.

Countrywide Financial Corp (Now part of Bank of America) AVM Specialist

November 2000 - August 2005 (4 years 10 months)

Designed and implemented statistical and intelligent models for Countrywide Home Loan's residential property evaluation system (ValueFinder)

Louisiana Department of Natural Resources Engineer IV September 1996 - November 2000 (4 years 3 months)

Responsible for providing technical expertise and leadership to a diverse range of physical modeling studies of Louisiana coastal protection projects aimed at freshwater diversion, wetland restoration, beach protection, and barrier island restoration.

Education

Louisiana State University M.S. · (2002)

University of Florida M.E · (1994 - 1996)

Hohai University